Vinício Oliveira

BIOINFORMATICS | SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

Guimarães, Portugal

vinimig.github.io

vinicio.mpv.oliveira@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Versatile and curiosity driven Bioinformatician by education, with 4+ years of experience in Software Development for High Content Screening. Currently deeply interested in the world of Artificial Intelligence and looking to earn my place in it.

KEYWORDS

Python, R, TIBCO Spotfire, Software Development, Data Visualization, Dashboards, Web Development (HTML, CSS, javascript, PHP, React), Machine Learning Deep Learning, Life Science

EDUCATION -

Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal Master's degree in Bioinformatics, 2015

Universidade do Minho

Braga, Portugal
BSc in Biochemistry, 2012
Erasmus student at Universitá degli studi
di Milano Statale, Milan, Italy, 2012

Machine Learning by Stanford University & DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on November 5, 2023
https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/MGBXTKY3S76S

Deep Learning by DeepLearning.Al on Coursera.

Certificate earned on March 30, 2024
https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/YFVXX53SHW4L

EXPERIENCE

July 2021 – October 2022

TIBCO Spotfire Consultant • BinarySeason

Development of interactive analysis dashboards with TIBCO Spotfire platform, for the pharma industry, mainly using IronPython, HTML and javascript. Additionally, some simple SQL queries for data retrieval. Gathered requirements and implemented a set of dashboards for the different stakeholder groups within the client company accordingly.

April 2020 – December 2020

Sr Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer

Research and Development of analytical applications for High Content Screening and Drug Discovery with the TIBCO Spotfire API (C# and R). Frequently collaborated with QA team to perform BDD testing. Higher responsibility in the lifecycle of applications playing a wider role in the development of the same.

August 2016 – April 2020

Software Development Engineer • PerkinElmer

Contributed to the R&D team with implementation of the R analytical methods for applications under the TIBCO Spotfire platform. Initial contributions using the C# API and regular participation in code reviews and contact with QA testing.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese (Native)

English (Proficient)

Spanish (Advanced)

Italian (Intermediate)